Shad, John S. R. John S. R. Shad papers, 1972-1989 (inclusive): A Finding Aid
John S. R. Shad papers, 1972-1989 (inclusive)
- I. Speeches and writings, 1981-1988
  - Keynote address, SEC Securities Immobilization Workshop, Washington, D.C., February 25, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 4, f. 37)
  - Remarks, SEC Black History Program, Washington, D.C., February 27, 1985. (Box Box 4, f. 38)
  - Remarks, SEC Black History Program, Washington, D.C., February 27, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 4, f. 39)
  - “SEC Speaks 1985,” Practicing Law Institute, Washington, D.C.,. March 1, 1985 (Box Box 4, f. 40)
  - “SEC Speaks 1985,” Practicing Law Institute, Washington, D.C., March 1, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 4, f. 41)
  - Remarks, American Business Conference, Washington, D.C., March 13, 1985. (Box Box 4, f. 42)
  - Speech, The Vice President's Task Group on Regulation of Financial Services—Securities Law Recommendations, March 22, 1985. (Box Box 4, f. 43)
  - Remarks, Conference on Bush Task Group Report, National Center on Financial Services, University of California, March 23, 1985. (Box Box 4, f. 44)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” The Conference Board, Pebble Beach, Calif., March 24, 1985. (Box Box 4, f. 45)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” The Conference Board, Pebble Beach, Calif., March 24, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 4, f. 46)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” Society of American Business and Economic Writers, May 7, 1985. (Box Box 4, f. 47)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” Society of American Business and Economic Writers, May 7, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 4, f. 48)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” Arthur Anderson and Co. Partners’ Meeting, May 13, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 4, f. 49)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” National Republican Committee, Washington, D.C., June 7, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 1)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” National Republican Committee, Washington, D.C., June 7, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 2)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” Fay Improvement Company Seminar, Washington, D.C., June 18, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 3)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” Fay Improvement Company Seminar, Washington, D.C., June 18, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 4)
  - Remarks, NYSE Meeting with CFOs, June 24, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 5)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” Women in Government Relations, Washington, D.C., July 3, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 6)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” Women in Government Relations, Washington, D.C., July 3, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 7)
  - Keynote remarks, Fourth Annual Government Business Forum on Small Business Capital Formation, Washington, D.C., September 12, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 8)
  - “Current Commission Policies and Developments Related to Financial Services Issues,” Conference of the National Center on Financial Services, Washington, D.C., October 11, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 9)
  - “Current Commission Policies and Developments Related to Financial Services Issues,” Conference of the National Center on Financial Services, Washington, D.C., October 11, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 10)
  - Remarks, Immobilization Forum at NYSE with Investment Bankers, New York, October 21, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 11)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” First Annual Meeting, Council of Institutional Investors, Atlanta, Georgia, October 29, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 12)
  - “Major Efforts and Issues at the SEC,” First Annual Meeting, Council of Institutional Investors, Atlanta, Georgia, October 29, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 13)
  - “Things to Come in the Securities Markets,” New York Arthritis Foundation Dinner, New York, N. Y., November 20, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 14)
  - “Things to Come in the Securities Markets,” New York Arthritis Foundation Dinner, New York, N. Y., November 20, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 15)
  - “The Security Industry and Markets: Past, Present and Future,” Securities Industry Association, Boca Raton, Fla., December 5, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 16)
  - “The Security Industry and Markets: Past, Present and Future,” Securities Industry Association, Boca Raton, Fla., December 5, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 17)
  - “The Security Industry and Markets: Past, Present and Future,” National Press Club, Washington, D.C., December 11, 1985. (Box Box 5, f. 18)
  - “The Security Industry and Markets: Past, Present and Future,” National Press Club, Washington, D.C., December 11, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 19)
  - “Major SEC Efforts and Issues,” The Conference Board, New York, N. Y., January 29, 1986(speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 20)
  - “SEC Speaks 1986: An Overview of Recent SEC Results and Ongoing Efforts, Practicing Law Institute, Washington, D.C., March 7, 1986. (Box Box 5, f. 21)
  - “SEC Speaks 1986: An Overview of Recent SEC Results and Ongoing Efforts, Practicing Law Institute, Washington, D.C., March 7, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 22)
  - “Joint State and Federal Efforts,” North American Securities Administrators Association, Annual Meeting, Washington, D.C., March 11, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 23)
  - Remarks, National Center on Financial Services, San Francisco, Calif., March 14, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 24)
  - Remarks, Conference Board CFOs, Boca Raton, Fla., March 21, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 25)
  - “Misperceptions,” Harvard Business School Club of New York, April 11, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 26)
  - “Certificate Immobilization,” SIA [Securities Industry Association] Securities Operations Division, May 16, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 27)
  - “Functional Regulation: The Concept and Its Applications,” Exchequer Club, Washington, D.C., May 21, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 28)
  - Opening statement, SEC Roundtable on Financial Reporting and the Role of the Independent Auditor, June 3, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 29)
  - Opening remarks, Fifth Annual SEC Government-Business Forum on Small Business Capital Formation, September 25, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 30)
  - “Introduction of the Honorable Doug Barnard, Jr.,” SEC Government-Business Forum on Small Business Capital Formation, September 25, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 31)
  - “International Securities Markets: Benefits and Challenges,” Atlantic Exchange Program, October 6, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 32)
  - “Insider Trading, Program Trading, and the Internationalization of the Securities Markets,” Harvard Business School Finance Club, October 17, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 33)
  - Press conference remarks, Ivan Boesky settlement, November 14, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 34)
  - Remarks, Swearing-in of Kathleen A. Warwick, January 9, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 35)
  - “The Benefits and Challenges of the Increasing Internationalization of the Securities Markets,” Garn Institute of Finance, January 12, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 36)
  - “The Benefits and Challenges of the Increasing Internationalization of the Securities Markets,” Hoover Institution, Washington, D. C., January 14, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 37)
  - “Questions Raised by Recent Insider Trading Cases Involving Graduates of Leading Business and Law Schools,” Beta Gamma Sigma, New York University Club, January 30, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 38)
  - “Broader Issues Raised by Recent Insider Trading Cases,” Association of Business Publishers, Washington, D. C., February 4, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 39)
  - “Broader Issues Raised by Recent Insider Trading Cases,” Washington Journalism Center, Washington, D. C., March 10, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 40)
  - Opening remarks, Joint SEC/NASAA [North American Securities Administrators Association] Hearing, March 16, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 41)
  - “Broader Issues Raised by Recent Insider Trading Cases,” National Legal Center for the Public Interest, Washington, D. C., March 24, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 42)
  - Lunch remarks, First Boston, May 11, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 43)
  - Acceptance remarks, Keough Award, New York University Alumni Federation, May 27, 1987(speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 44)
  - Dinner remarks, June 6, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 45)
  - “Business Leadership and Ethics,” Harvard Business School Club of Washington, D. C., June 10, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 46)
  - Remarks, Staff Going-Away Party, June 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 47)
  - Remarks, Commissioners and Senior Staff Reception, June 16, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 5, f. 48)
  - News clippings quoting or mentioning John S. R. Shad, October 1981-January 1982. (Box Box 5, f. 49)
  - Writings: “Reagan’s Farm-Plan Stakes are No Small Beans”, Wall Street Journal, October 20, 1987. (Box Box 5, f. 50)
  - Writings: “Raise Futures and Options Margins Now”, Wall Street Journal, January 15, 1988. (Box Box 5, f. 51)
- II. Congressional testimony, 1981-1987
  This series contains copies of many of the statements that Mr. Shad delivered before Congress. As chairman, Mr. Shad was frequently called upon to testify before the various House and Senate committees and subcommittees that oversee the Securities and Exchange Commission. Mr. Shad’s testimony covered many of the important issues that faced the S. E. C. and the securities industry in the 1980s: regulatory reform and paperwork reduction; the commission’s annual budget request and reauthorization; amendments to laws concerning the S. E. C.’s regulatory authority; the commission’s enforcement efforts, including insider trading cases; and the effect of technology on the operation of the securities markets.
  The files contain one or both of the following for each appearance Chairman Shad made before Congress: 1) a written copy of Mr. Shad’s opening statement or oral testimony; 2) a more detailed written statement that was submitted to Congress as official testimony. There are also “speaking copies” of some of the opening statements and oral testimonies; these are edited and annotated copies that Mr. Shad used to deliver his remarks. The testimony files are arranged chronologically.
  - Oral testimony before Joint Hearings of the Subcommittee on Securities and the Subcommittee on International Finance and Monetary Policy of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs concerning S. 708 [Foreign Corrupt Practices Act], June 16, 1981. (Box 6, f. 1)
  - Written statement before Joint Hearings of the Subcommittee on Securities and the Subcommittee on International Finance and Monetary Policy of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs concerning S. 708 [Foreign Corrupt Practices Act], June 16, 1981. (Box 6, f. 2)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce [securities industry overview], June 18, 1981. (Box 6, f. 3)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce [securities industry overview], June 18, 1981. (Box 6, f. 4)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations [FY1982 budget revisions], October 27, 1981. (Box 6, f. 5)
  - Oral statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs regarding S.1720 and S.1721 [amendments to Glass-Steagall Act], October 30, 1981. (Box 6, f. 6)
  - Written testimony before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs regarding S.1720 and S.1721 [amendments to Glass-Steagall Act], October 30, 1981. (Box 6, f. 7)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning the SEC’s Administration and Enforcement of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977, November 18, 1981. (Box 6, f. 8)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning the SEC’s administration and enforcement of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977, November 18, 1981. (Box 6, f. 9)
  - Opening statement before Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs regarding the Treasury Department’s proposed Bank Holding Company Deregulation Act, February 4, 1982. (Box 6, f. 10)
  - Opening statement before Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs regarding the Treasury Department’s proposed Bank Holding Company Deregulation Act, February 4, 1982 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 11)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary and related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1983 budget request], March 2, 1982. (Box 6, f. 12)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary and related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1983 budget request], March 2, 1982. (Box 6, f. 13)
  - Opening statement before Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs regarding S. 2260 [concerning the SEC/CFTC Accord], March 31, 1982. (Box 6, f. 14)
  - Written statement before Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs regarding S. 2260 [concerning the SEC/CFTC Accord], March 31, 1982. (Box 6, f. 15)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittees on Oversight and Investigation and Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning options and futures on financial instruments, April 23, 1982. (Box 6, f. 16)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittees on Oversight and Investigation and Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning options and futures on financial instruments, April 23, 1982. (Box 6, f. 17)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on State, Justice, Commerce, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the Senate Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1983 budget request], May 27, 1982. (Box 6, f. 18)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittees on Oversight and Investigations and Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning the SEC/CFTC [Commodities Futures Trading Commission] Accord, June 7, 1982. (Box 6, f. 19)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittees on Oversight and Investigations and Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning the SEC/CFTC [Commodities Futures Trading Commission] Accord, June 7, 1982. (Box 6, f. 20)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning the Public Utility Holding Company Act, June 8, 1982. (Box 6, f. 21)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning the Public Utility Holding Company Act, June 8, 1982 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 22)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning the Public Utility Holding Company Act, June 8, 1982 (speaking copy) (Box 6, f. 23)
  - Written statement of the U. S. Securities and Exchange Commission concerning proposals to amend or repeal the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935, June 2, 1982 (presented June 8, 1982). (Box 6, f. 24)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Energy, Conservation, and Power of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning the Public Utility Holding Company Act, June 9, 1982. (Box 6, f. 25)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Energy, Conservation, and Power of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning the Public Utility Holding Company Act, June 9, 1982 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 26)
  - Opening statement, Securities and Exchange Commission meeting on Glass-Steagall matters, July 7, 1982. (Box 6, f. 27)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, and Rural Development of the House Committee on Agriculture concerning SEC/CFTC [Commodities Futures Trading Commission] Accord, July 15, 1982. (Box 6, f. 28)
  - Oral statement, VISA Hearings, September 20, 1982. (Box 6, f. 29)
  - Press release, “SEC 1982 Results and Ongoing Efforts,” February 7, 1983. (Box 6, f. 30)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1984 budget request], February 8, 1983. (Box 6, f. 31)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1984 budget request], February 8, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 32)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce [regarding SEC reauthorization], February 15, 1983. (Box 6, f. 33)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce [regarding SEC reauthorization], February 15, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 34)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on International Finance and Monetary Policy of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning S. 414 [Foreign Corrupt Practices Act], February 24, 1983. (Box 6, f. 35)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on International Finance and Monetary Policy of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning S. 414 [Foreign Corrupt Practices Act], February 24, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 36)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on State, Justice, Commerce, and the Judiciary of the Senate Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1984 budget request], March 16, 1983. (Box 6, f. 37)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on State, Justice, Commerce, and the Judiciary of the Senate Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1984 budget request], March 16, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 38)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs [Thomas Reed insider trading investigation], March 22, 1983 (Box 6, f. 39)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs [Thomas Reed insider trading investigation], March 22, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 40)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs [SEC reauthorization], March 25, 1983. (Box 6, f. 41)
  - Addendum to testimony before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs [SEC reauthorization], March 25, 1983. (Box 6, f. 42)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Energy and Commerce Committee concerning the Insider Trading Sanctions Act, April 13, 1983. (Box 6, f. 43)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Energy and Commerce Committee concerning the Insider Trading Sanctions Act, April 13, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 44)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Energy and Commerce Committee concerning the Insider Trading Sanctions Act, April 13, 1983. (Box 6, f. 45)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation, and Insurance of the House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs [public disclosures of material information], April 21, 1983. (Box 6, f. 46)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation, and Insurance of the House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs [public disclosures of material information], April 21, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box 6, f. 47)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation, and Insurance of the House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs [public disclosures of material information], April 21, 1983. (Box 6, f. 48)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs [proposed changes in regulation of financial services industries], June 8, 1983. (Box 6, f. 49)
  - Written statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs [proposed changes in regulation of financial services industries], June 8, 1983. (Box 6, f. 50)
  - Opening statement before Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs regarding S. 1174 to amend the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935, June 15, 1983. (Box Box 7, f. 1)
  - Written statement before Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs regarding S. 1174 to amend the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935, June 15, 1983. (Box Box 7, f. 2)
  - Opening statement before House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Customer Protection, and Finance [Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. proposal re: underwriting of corporate securities], June 16, 1983. (Box Box 7, f. 3)
  - Written statement before House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Customer Protection, and Finance [Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. proposal re: underwriting of corporate securities], June 16, 1983. (Box Box 7, f. 4)
  - Oral statement before the House Judiciary Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations [regulatory reform legislation], July 27, 1983. (Box Box 7, f. 5)
  - Oral statement before the House Judiciary Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations [regulatory reform legislation], July 27, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 6)
  - Summary statement before the House Judiciary Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations [regulatory reform legislation], July 27, 1983. (Box Box 7, f. 7)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs regarding the Hot New Issue Market, December 15, 1983. (Box Box 7, f. 8)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs regarding the Hot New Issue Market, December 15, 1983 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 9)
  - Written statement of John S. R. Shad, Chairman, and John M. Fedders, Director, Division of Enforcement, of the Securities and Exchange Commission, before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs regarding the Hot New Issue Market, December 15, 1983. (Box Box 7, f. 10)
  - Remarks before the Subcommittee on Mining, Forest Management, and the Bonneville Power Administration ("BPA") of the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs [SEC monitoring of supply system],January 26, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 11)
  - Remarks before the Subcommittee on Mining, Forest Management, and the Bonneville Power Administration ("BPA") of the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs [SEC monitoring of supply system], January 26, 1984 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 12)